

BUSINESS AND TECH STUDENT · ENTREPRENEURSHIP AND AI ENTHUSIAST

Kreuzstraße 3, 76133 Karlsruhe, Germany

□ +49 162 7901840 | Imail@tobias-budig.com | Marwww.tobias-budig.com | Imatobias-budig

"Building the Future with Tech"



Profile

Current student of business engineering with focus on computer science at Karlsruhe Institute of Technology (KIT), Germany. Served as chairman and other positions at Germany's largest student society for entrepreneurship and innovation, PionierGarage e.V. Worked on different private software projects as well as freelance positions. Interested in deep-tech to solve real world problems.

Education

Semester abroad Stockholm, Sweden

KTH (Royal Institute of Technology)

Aug. 2020 - Jan. 2021

· Courses: Artificial Intelligence and Applications, Network Programming, Marketing Management, Entrepreneurship, Swedish A1

B.Sc. in Business and Engineering

Karlsruhe, Germany

KIT (KARLSRUHE INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY)

Oct. 2018 - today

• Focus on Computer Science, Operations Research and Digital Business • current GPA: 1,9 (top 25%)

Physics Göttingen, Germany

University of Göttingen

Oct. 2017 - Sep. 2018

Mathematics 1 & 2 and experimental physics 1 & 2

Abitur (A-Level equivalent)

Minden, Germany

Besselgymnasium Minden

Jul. 2017

• Advanced courses: Mathematics, Physics • GPA: 1,0 (top 2%)

Work Experience _____

Co-Founder & CTO Karlsruhe, Germany

MUN Command Jan. 2020 - Today

- MUN Command is the all-in-one SaaS solution for model united nation conferences (muncommand.com)
- Responsible for selection of tech-stack as well as for entrepreneurial and innovative methods.
- Designing software architecture and programming an Angular web-app with GraphQL and Firebase backend.

Tutor Mathematics 2 Karlsruhe, Germany

KARLSRUHER INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY (KIT)

Apr. 2020 - Aug. 2020

• Teaching students multivariate calculus and linear algebra remote.

Working Student as Assistant to Founder

Karlsruhe, Germany

HELIOPAS.AI GMBH

Dez. 2019 - Jul. 2020

· Supporting founders in day-to-day business with focus on finances and processes as well as pressing technical topics.

Student Assistant Göttingen, Germany

LASER LABORATORIUM GÖTTINGEN E.V.

Jan. 2018 - Sep. 2018

Analysing materials with Raman spectroscope; Analysing data in Python; Experimenting with electric-chemical-cells to produce a SERS active
material.

Intern as Executive Assistant to CIO

Frankfurt a.M., Germany

QX-Quarterly Crossing GmbH

Feb. 2018 - Apr. 2018

• Planning and recruiting participants for Events. Process optimization, introducing digital tools. Supporting of CIO in day-to-day business

Freelance web developer

Germany

SELF-EMPLOYED

Aug. 2017 - May. 2019

• Building websites and optimizing online presence of customers

November 22, 2020 Tobias Budig · Résumé



Practical Deep Learning for Coders

Online, fast.ai

FAST.AI 20

• In this course, we start by showing how to use a complete, state-of-the-art deep learning network to solve real-world problems. And then we gradually dig deeper and deeper into understanding how those tools are made.

Machine Learning Online Course

Online, Cousera

STANFORD UNIVERSITY ON COURSERA

2018

· This course provides a broad introduction to machine learning, datamining, and statistical pattern recognition.

Extracurricular Activity

Chairman and other roles

Karlsruhe, Germany

PIONIERGARAGE E.V. (PG)

Oct. 2018 - today

- The PionierGarage is the university group for entrepreneurship and innovation at KIT. It offers events and runs a co-working space for students.
- 08/20 today: Member of PG Academy, aiming to bring PG Academy to whole Germany
- 02/20 08/20: Advisory Board for new board; Head of PG Academy (Entrepreneurship education for students)
- 08/19 02/20: **Chairman** responsible for 30+ members
- 02/19 08/19: **CFO** responsible for 60 k€ budget
- 10/18 02/19: Member of marketing department

Honors & Awards

Nov. 2020 Award for outstanding voluntary commitment, by Karlsruher Institute of Technology

Germany

Oct. 2019 Scholarship by Friedrich Naumann Foundation for Freedom,

Germany

Feb. 2019 **1st Place GROW Founding Contest.** Local founding contest with 31 teams participating.

Karlsruhe, Germany

Mar. 2018 **ICU Scholarship**, The one-year leadership scholarship for students for all disciplines

Frankfurt, Germany

Jun. 2017 **Special award "Artificial Intelligence"**, Jugend Gründet (domestic youth founding competition).

Stuttgart, Germany

Skills

Languages German (Native), English (Fluent), French (Basics), Swedish (Basics)

Software Photoshop, Premiere Pro, Notion, WordPress, LaTeX

Entrepreneurial Design Thinking, Business Model Canvas, Lean Startup, Rapid Prototyping

Web Stack Angular, GraphQL, Hasura,

Programming Typescript, JavaScript, Python, Java

November 22, 2020 Tobias Budig · Résumé